

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Full-Stack Web Developer**

ACLTC Chicago, IL | 2016

## **MS** in Educational Leadership

Aurora University Aurora, IL | 2007

## **Teacher Cert/BS in Biology**

Northern Illinois University Dekalb, IL | 2003

### **BA in Biology**

Indiana University Bloomington, IN | 1999

## **SKILLS**

Ruby

Rails

Javascript

Angular JS

Git

Jekyll

SQL

Bootstrap

HTML

CSS

## **CONTACT**

Chicago, IL 224-456-8338 ryanlennon07@gmail.com github.com/ryanlennon linkedin.com/in/ryanlennon07

website

ryanlennon.github.io/

## **Full-Stack Web Developer**

#### BIO

Creative problem-solver with a passion for software development. Professional collaborator with well-defined communication skills and a desire to continually grow and improve. Experienced leader and time manager with proven adaptability to learn quickly and implement concepts effectively.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# ACHAW | Chicago, IL | Jan 2016 - Present Web Developer Intern - Kaizen

- Create and Design functional app using Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Twilio API, and Heroku
- Organize and collaborate with co-workers to improve and enhance development and ensure best practice
- Construct and use test driven data methods

# ACLTC | Chicago, IL | Oct 2015 – Jan 2016 Full Stack Developer in-Training

- Developed functional e-commerce app utilizing Ruby, Rails, and SQL
- Helped other students understand Ruby and JavaScript concepts
- Worked in teams and pair-programmed with other students
- Capstone Project: Tee Box
  - Allows users to locate a golf course and view course specific information
  - Users can reserve/purchase a tee time
  - Utilizes Rails, SQL, HTML\CSS, Bootstrap, google maps API, and weather API

## Grant High School | Fox Lake, IL | Aug 2004 - Present Educator

- Facilitate engaging and dynamic lessons with an emphasis on improving students' problem perception, analytical thinking, and communication skills
- Design lesson plans in line with state curriculum and standards
- Instruct students to utilize problem solving methodology and techniques during classroom activities, labs, projects
- Plan, implement, monitor, and assess classroom instructional lessons in multiple subject areas for regular and honors classes
- Collaborate with colleagues to develop and align science curriculum with state standards
- Create curriculum in several subjects to meet the next-generation implementation deadline
- Coach a range of sport-specific skills in basketball and football while developing game plans and adjusting them as needed